Previously on the show.
ความเดิมตอนที่แล้ว
Mechanical Bird drove a big plane to the Cloud Sea Tunnel
หุ่นยนต์นกขับเครื่องบินลำใหญ่ ไปที่อุโมงค์ทะเลเมฆา
and chased Wolffy away with Slowy.
และร่วมมือกับสโลวี่ขับไล่วูฟฟี่ไป
To the goats' surprise, Slowy was Mechanical Bird's teacher.
เรื่องเซอร์ไพรส์ของพวกแกะก็คือ สโลวี่คือคุณครูของหุ่นยนต์นก
What happened between them in the past?
พวกเขาเคยมีเรื่องอะไรกันในอดีตนะ
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: Bygone Memories"
"แกะน้อยสุดกวนกับหมาป่าจอมป่วน ตอน ความทรงจำในอดีต"
What happened back then, Master?
อาจารย์ เมื่อก่อนโน้นมีเรื่องอะไรกันเหรอ
Why were you separated from Village Chief?
ทำไมถึงแยกกันอยู่กับหัวหน้าหมู่บ้านล่ะ
I remember back then,
ฉันยังจำได้ตอนนั้นได้เลย
Teacher and I were preparing for a sky adventure...
คุณครูกับฉันกำลังเตรียมตัวไปผจญภัยกลางเวหา
After all this time, our dream is finally coming true.
หลังจากที่เฝ้ารอมานาน ในที่สุดฝันของเราก็เป็นจริง
Are you ready, Mechanical Bird?
พร้อมไหมล่ะ หุ่นยนต์นก
Yes!
พร้อมแล้ว!
Well, then... let's go!
ถ้างั้นก็ไปกันเลย!
Teacher, you pressed the wrong button.
คุณครูกดปุ่มผิดแล้วล่ะ
That was just a minor mistake.
นั่นก็แค่เรื่องผิดพลาดเล็กน้อยน่า
Let's go!
ไปกันเลย!
This is breath-taking. It's a completely different view from the grasslands.
โอ้โหสวยน่าทึ่งสุดๆ ไปเลย แตกต่างจากที่เคยเห็นจากทุ่งหญ้าเลยนะ
Can we fly higher, Teacher?
คุณครู เราบินขึ้นไปสูงกว่านี้ได้ไหม
No problem.
ได้สิไม่มีปัญหา
Oh, no, there's a super thunderstorm ahead.
แย่ล่ะสิ มีพายุฝนฟ้าคะนองลูกใหญ่อยู่ข้างหน้า
Dodge!
หลบเร็ว!
Mechanical Bird!
หุ่นยนต์นก!
Are you all right?
นายเป็นอะไรรึเปล่า
I'm fine.
ไม่เป็นไร
Emergency exit opens...
ทางออกฉุกเฉินเปิด...
Oh, no, air currents are getting inside the plane.
แย่แล้ว มีกระแสลมพัดเข้ามาในเครื่องบิน
Hang on tight, Mechanical Bird!
จับไว้แน่นๆ นะ หุ่นยนต์นก!
Mechanical Bird!
หุ่นยนต์นก!
Teacher!
คุณครู!
I thought I'd never see you again.
ผมนึกว่าจะไม่ได้เจอคุณอีกแล้ว
Where did you go after that?
หลังจากนั้นคุณไปไหนต่อเหรอ
I'm not sure, to be honest.
พูดตรงๆ นะฉันก็ไม่แน่ใจเหมือนกัน
I was already in Goats Village when I woke up.
พอตื่นขึ้นมาก็อยู่ในหมู่บ้านแกะแล้วน่ะสิ
I wonder what happened before Village Chief woke up.
สงสัยจังว่าเกิดเรื่องอะไรขึ้น ก่อนที่หัวหน้าหมู่บ้านจะตื่น
What is going on?
เกิดอะไรขึ้นเนี่ย
This kind of tremor, could it be...
การสั่นสะเทือนแบบนี้ หรือว่าจะเป็น...
Look at that! That is...
ดูนั่นสิ! นั่นคือ...
That big guy is sucking all the cloud people in.
เจ้าตัวโตนั่นดูดชาวเมฆาเข้าไปในตัวได้ด้วย
What is he chasing after?
เขาวิ่งไล่ตามอะไรอยู่นะ
Wolffy!
วูฟฟี่!
Help!
ช่วยด้วย!
Wait! Stop!
เดี๋ยวก่อน! หยุดก่อน!
I didn't do anything to you. Why are you chasing after me?
ผมไม่ได้ทำอะไรคุณเลยนะ ทำไมถึงมาวิ่งไล่ตามผมล่ะ
It's the goats.
พวกแกะต่างหากล่ะ
They are coming! Run!
พวกเขามากันแล้ว! หนีเร็ว!
Don't run!
อย่าหนีนะ!
I just want you to help me get rid of this big guy.
ฉันแค่อยากให้นายช่วยจัดการกับเจ้าตัวโตนี้หน่อย
Don't drag us into this.
อย่าลากผมเข้าไปเกี่ยวด้วยเลยฮะ
You dropped this. Here you go.
นายทำนี่หล่นไว้น่ะ เอาไปสิ
Oh, you wanted to return something.
อ๋อ คุณจะเอาของมาคืนนี่เอง
Why didn't you tell me?
ทำไมไม่บอกกันก่อนล่ะ
I told you to wait. You wouldn't stop.
ก็บอกให้รอเดี๋ยว นายก็ไม่หยุดนี่นา
You're so gigantic and scary. How could I not run?
ก็คุณตัวบิ๊กเบิ้มและน่ากลัว จะไม่ให้ผมวิ่งหนีได้ยังไงล่ะ
It's not my fault I'm gigantic.
ไม่ใช่ความผิดฉันนะที่ตัวบิ๊กเบิ้มน่ะ
Cloud Giant, you're back.
จอมพลังเมฆา กลับมาแล้วเหรอ
Everyone, he's the cloud giant I mentioned.
ทุกคนจ๊ะ นั่นคือจอมพลังเมฆาที่ฉันเคยพูดถึงไงล่ะ
But why did he suck in all the cloud people?
แต่ทำไมเขาถึงดูดชาวเมฆาเข้าไปในตัวล่ะ
They are a part of him.
พวกนั้นเป็นส่วนหนึ่งของเขาน่ะสิ
Jonie, they must be your friends.
โจนี่ พวกเขาคงเป็นเพื่อนๆ ของเธอสินะ
So the goats know about this big guy.
งั้นพวกแกะก็รู้จักชายตัวโตคนนี้น่ะสิ
Fine, since it's a misunderstanding, I'll be going now.
ในเมื่อเป็นเรื่องเข้าใจผิดกันก็ดีแล้ว ฉันไปดีกว่า
Cloud Giant, so you weren't chasing after Wolffy because of the sky crystal?
จอมพลังเมฆาไม่ได้ไล่ตามวูฟฟี่ เพื่อจะเอาคริสตัลเมฆาเหรอ
Sky crystal?
คริสตัลเมฆาเหรอ
What are you doing?
คุณจะทำอะไรน่ะ
Spill it. What do you have to do with the sky crystal?
บอกความจริงมานะ นายจะเอาคริสตัลเมฆาไปทำอะไร
I have nothing to do with it.
ผมไม่ได้จะเอาไปทำอะไรนะ
The sky crystal fell from the sky. I found it.
คริสตัลเมฆาร่วงลงมาจากท้องฟ้า แล้วผมไปเจอเข้าน่ะ
What? Shouldn't you say the sky crystal was stolen by a bird?
อะไรนะ นายบอกว่าคริสตัลเมฆา ถูกนกขโมยไปไม่ใช่เหรอ
Think carefully. Don't blame the innocent.
คิดให้ดีๆ สิ อย่ามาโทษผู้บริสุทธิ์นะ
What is going on, Cloud Giant?
มีเรื่องอะไรกันเหรอ จอมพลังเมฆา
I remember back then...
ฉันจำได้ตอนนั้น...
I was going after the thief who stole the sky crystal.
ฉันไล่ตามโจรที่ขโมยคริสตัลเมฆาไป
Don't run! Give it back to me!
อย่าหนีนะ! เอาคืนมานะ!
Close your eyes.
จงหลับตา!
Give the sky crystal back.
ส่งคริสตัลเมฆาคืนมานะ!
I won't give it back to you!
ฉันไม่คืนให้นายแน่ๆ!
Because of that super thunderstorm, the thief got away.
เพราะพายุฝนฟ้าคะนองลูกใหญ่นั่น เจ้าโจรจึงหนีไปได้
So the thief should still have the sky crystal.
ดังนั้นเจ้าโจรนั่นต้องมีคริสตัลเมฆาอยู่แน่ๆ
There's only one explanation then.
ถ้างั้นเรื่องนี้ก็มีแค่คำอธิบายเดียวแหละ
The thief threw the sky crystal away.
เจ้าโจรนั่นคงโยนคริสตัลเมฆาทิ้งไปแล้ว
Super thunderstorm?
พายุฝนฟ้าคะนองเหรอ
Did you see a plane like this then?
ถ้างั้นคุณเคยเห็นเครื่องบินแบบนี้มั้ย
It looks familiar. I think I saw it when I fell.
ดูคุ้นๆ จัง ฉันคิดว่าเคยเห็นตอนที่ตัวเองหกล้มนะ
So the thief created the thunderstorm we got caught in.
ถ้างั้นโจรก็สร้างพายุฝนฟ้าคะนอง เราก็เลยติดอยู่ในพายุไงล่ะ
I almost died because you tripped and fell.
ผมเกือบตายเพราะว่าคุณหกล้มหล่นลงมาเนี่ยนะ
What? How is that related to you?
อะไรนะ เรื่องนี้ไปเกี่ยวอะไรกับนายล่ะ
Of course, because I was on Slowy's plane too.
ก็ต้องเกี่ยวสิ เพราะผมอยู่บนเครื่องบินของสโลวี่ด้วยน่ะสิ
I planned to catch a goat to finish my summer assignment.
ผมวางแผนจับแกะเป็นการส่งท้ายภารกิจฤดูร้อน
This goat is so slow. I'll make him my target.
แกะตัวนี้ช้าดีจัง งั้นพุ่งเป้าไปที่ตัวนี้ดีกว่า
So I sneaked into Slowy's plane.
ผมแอบเข้าไปในเครื่องบินของสโลวี่
After all this time, our dream is finally coming true.
หลังจากที่เฝ้ารอมานาน ในที่สุดฝันของเราก็เป็นจริง
Are you ready, Mechanical Bird?
พร้อมรึยังล่ะ หุ่นยนต์นก
-Yes! -Let's go!
- พร้อมแล้ว! - ไปกันเลย!
Teacher, you pressed the wrong button.
คุณครูกดปุ่มผิดแล้วล่ะ
That was just a minor mistake. Let's go!
นั่นก็แค่เรื่องผิดพลาดเล็กน้อยน่า ไปกันเลย!
I must catch a goat this time and prove myself to Cousin Darker.
คราวนี้เราต้องจับแกะให้ได้ เพื่อพิสูจน์ตัวเองกับเจ้าดาร์กเกอร์ญาติฉัน
Can we fly higher, Teacher?
คุณครู เราบินขึ้นไปสูงกว่านี้ได้ไหม
No problem.
ได้สิไม่มีปัญหา
Oh, no, there's a super thunderstorm ahead.
แย่ล่ะสิ มีพายุฝนฟ้าคะนองลูกใหญ่อยู่ข้างหน้า
Dodge!
หลบเร็ว!
What's going on?
เกิดอะไรขึ้นเนี่ย
Emergency exit opens.
ประตูฉุกเฉินเปิดแล้ว
Oh, no, air currents are getting inside the plane.
แย่แล้ว มีกระแสลมพัดเข้ามาในเครื่องบิน
Hang on tight, Mechanical Bird!
จับไว้แน่นๆ นะ หุ่นยนต์นก!
Mechanical Bird!
หุ่นยนต์นก!
Cousin can't tease me anymore when I bring this goat back.
ถ้าฉันจับแกะนี้กลับไปได้ ญาติก็เลิกล้อฉันซะที
Who threw that?
ใครโยนมาเนี่ย
This rock looks special. I'm taking it home.
หินก้อนนี้ดูพิเศษจัง ฉันเอากลับบ้านด้วยดีกว่า
Just as I picked up the gem,
ตอนนั้นแหละที่ผมเก็บเพชรได้น่ะ
this giant fell out of the sky and smashed the plane.
พี่เบิ้มนี่ร่วงลงมาจากฟ้าแล้วก็ชนกับเครื่องบิน
Cloud Giant! So it was you who broke the plane!
จอมพลังเมฆา! นายนี่เองที่ทำเครื่องบินพัง!
I'm so sorry.
ฉันขอโทษจริงๆ นะ
It was really chaotic,
มันวุ่นวายจริงๆ นะ
so I tripped and fell by accident.
ฉันก็เลยสะดุดและร่วงลงมาโดยไม่ได้ตั้งใจ
What happened afterwards, Wolffy?
วูฟฟี่ หลังจากนั้นเกิดอะไรขึ้นเหรอ
Cloud Giant's fall resulted in a huge shock wave.
การที่จอมพลังเมฆาหล่นลงมา ทำให้เกิดคลื่นกระแทกลูกยักษ์น่ะสิ
I'm doomed!
งานนี้ฉันตายแน่!
The parachute!
ร่มชูชีพ!
Why won't it open now?
ทำไมเปิดไม่ได้ล่ะ
Luckily, I opened the parachute in time.
โชคดีนะที่เรากางร่มชูชีพได้ทันเวลา
What happened after that, Wolffy?
วูฟฟี่ หลังจากนั้นเกิดเรื่องอะไรอีกเหรอ
Then we happened to land at the gate of Goats Village.
จากนั้นเราก็ลอยไปลงที่ หน้าประตูหมู่บ้านแกะพอดีเลย
A group of armed goats rushed towards me
กลุ่มแกะติดอาวุธก็วิ่งกรูเข้ามาหาฉัน
and rescued Slowy.
และช่วยสโลวี่
I escaped back to Wolf Fortress with the gem,
ฉันหนีกลับไปที่ป้อมหมาป่าพร้อมกับเพชรนั่น
only to realize it'd turned into a common purple color.
พอรู้ตัวอีกทีมันก็กลายเป็นหินธรรมดาสีม่วงไปแล้ว
Years later, during a home renovation,
หลายปีต่อมา ระหว่างที่ซ่อมแซมบ้าน
I embedded the gem into a photo frame.
ฉันจึงติดเพชรเม็ดนั้นลงไปในกรอบรูป
So you really found the sky crystal by accident.
ถ้างั้นนายก็เจอคริสตัลเมฆาโดยบังเอิญสินะ
Of course. I told you I was innocent.
แหงสิ ก็บอกแล้วว่าผมบริสุทธิ์น่ะ
Innocent? Then why are you carrying the weather fruit around?
บริสุทธิ์เหรอ แล้วทำไมต้องหอบลูกสี่ฤดูติดตัวไปด้วยล่ะ
You must be planning to catch us with it.
คุณคงวางแผนจะใช้ผลไม้นั่นจับเราล่ะสิ
Don't be silly. How can I catch goats with just one weather fruit?
อย่าโง่ไปหน่อยเลยน่า ฉันจะจับพวกแกะด้วยลูกสี่ฤดูลูกเดียวได้ไงล่ะ
Wolffy, you dropped many more.
วูฟฟี่ นายทำผลไม้นั่นหล่นเต็มไปหมดนะ
You have many weather fruits on you!
นายยังมีลูกสี่ฤดูติดตัวอยู่อีกเยอะล่ะสิ!
And you said you're not planning on catching us?
คุณยังบอกอีกว่ากำลังวางแผนจับเราใช่ไหม
Oh, no. I should get out of here.
แย่ล่ะสิ ฉันควรจะออกไปจากที่นี่แล้วล่ะ
Bye.
ไปก่อนนะ
He ran off.
เขาหนีไปแล้วล่ะ
Cloud Giant, since you are back
จอมพลังเมฆา ในเมื่อคุณกลับมาแล้ว
and we have the fragments of the sky crystal,
และเราก็มีชิ้นส่วนของคริสตัลเมฆา
let's put it back together.
งั้นเอามาต่อเข้าด้วยกันเถอะ
Sure.
ได้เลย
Let's go back!
กลับกันเถอะ!
Why did that thief throw away the sky crystal?
ทำไมโจรนั่นถึงโยนคริสตัลเมฆาทิ้งนะ
TO BE CONTINUED
(โปรดติดตามตอนต่อไป)